Alexander (Sasha) Mazurov

CERN, Geneva 23, Geneva CH-1211

T: +41 76 487 07 03

E: <u>alexander.mazurov@cern.ch</u>
L: <u>ch.linkedin.com/in/mazurov</u>
GitHub: <u>https://github.com/mazurov</u>

G+: https://plus.google.com/+AlexanderMazurov

Google Scholar: http://goo.gl/9d4OiV



Objective

Software development, distributed computing, evangelizing best practices.

Summary

I'm currently a Doctoral student at CERN and registered at the University of Ferrara (Italy). My expected date of completion is March 2014. During the last 7 years I was based at CERN where I was collaborating on the LHCb experiment. I worked at offline and online computing groups. I have developed configuration library and profiling auditor for core framework Gauc wrote backend and frontend for Run Database web interface. My PhD thesis is a physics analysis, in which ROOT and other powerful tools from LHCb software stack have been used a lot. I hold a master's degree in Computer Science from Lomonosov's Moscow State University (Russia).

I'm interested in the design and development of challenging projects where the reliability and the performances are crucial. Focused on software quality and best practices. Versatile and able to grasp new concepts quickly, always willing to learn.

Experienced in project collaboration and coordination in an international and multicultural environment. Autonomous, yet strong team player, with good communication skills.

Specialties:

- Python, C/C++, HTML5 (javascript, css), Java, XML and XSLT.
- Linux system administration
- Full development cycle management
- Database design (MySQL, Oracle and MongoDB)
- Git and svn source control management
- ROOT scientific data analysis tool.

Education

University of Ferrara (Italy)

Ph.D. Physics

2011 - March 2014, Physics department

Thesis title: "LHCb High Level Trigger profiling and \(\gamma \) production study"

Lomonosov's Moscow State University (Russia)

MSc. Computer Science and Mathematics

1997-2002, Calculate Mathematics & Cybernetic department

Applied mathematics and system programming speciality

Thesis title: "Object-relational environment"

Courses and Grants

CERN School of Computing. 2008 August INTAS-CERN grant. 2006-2007 CERN Summer Student. 2005, July-August

Experience

Software Developer, LHCb experiment, CERN

Switzerland, http://cern.ch 2011 - now: Doctoral student 2007 - 2011: Project associates program

Accomplishments

- CPU profiler for core software at LHCb experiment
- Gaudi parsers C++ library
- CastorFS file system
- Run database web application
- Setup of LHCb TWiki and helpdesk system
- γb production study

Software Developer, Institute for Nuclear Research

2002-2012, Moscow, Russia, http://www.inr.ru/eng/english.html

Physics analysis and software development

Open Source Projects

https://github.com/mazurov

Accomplishments

- Eslevels JavaScript scope levels analyzer based on escope library
- Eslevels SublimeText plugin SublimeText editor plugin for scope context coloring
- Escope demo JavaScript scope objects visualization
- Parsim C++ library for strings parsing

Web developer, ArtLebedev studio

2006-2007, Moscow, Russia, http://artlebedev.com

Accomplishments

- Content Management System Imprimatur
- Backend application for VTB24 bank website

Selected publications

Because of the large collaboration in which I work, I am an author on a very large number of papers, and the author list includes the entire collaboration. I list here a subset of papers in which I played a leading role.

"Advanced Modular Software Performance Monitoring", A Mazurov and B Couturier 2012 J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 396 052054 doi:10.1088/1742-6596/396/5/052054. Talk at the CHEP 2012 conference (New York)

"CASTORFS - A filesystem to access CASTOR", Alexander Mazurov and Niko Neufeld 2010 J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 219 052023 doi:10.1088/1742-6596/219/5/052023 Poster at the CHEP 2009 conference (Prague)

Languages	Fluent: English, Russian
Other interests	Running and powerlifting. I am keen to learn and develop new skills.
References	Dr. Marco Cattaneo , LHCb Computing Coordinator, CERN, Geneva, Switzerland CH-1211. Marco.Cattaneo@cern.ch Dr. Niko Neufeld, LHCb Online Project Leader Deputy, CERN, Geneva, Switzerland CH-1211. Niko.Neufeld@cern.ch Dr. Marco Clemencic, LHCb core software group, CERN, Geneva, Switzerland CH-1211. Marco.Clemencic@cern.ch